Guide to the James Purdy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1957-63; Series II; 1.5; (4 boxes)
  - POETRY
    - "Attention-bringing death", 1957
    - "Death Is an Evening Caller", 1957
    - "Dondé se fué?" (Box 12, Folder 271)
    - "The Eagle the Dove", [1957]
    - "Fields vineyards groves and orchards", 1957
    - "The Fruits of Success", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 272)
    - "Les Six Grands", [1957]
    - "Love", [1957]
    - "Memoirs of an Assassin", 1957 (Box 12, Folder 273)
    - "Merry-go-round horses and carrousel", 1957
    - "Odes", 1957 (Box 12, Folder 274)
    - "The Peacock beyond Garden Walls", 1957
    - "Poems dedicated to Carl van Vechten"
      - "Cuban Mocking-Bird" "Sea of Marmara" "In the Event of" "Birds" "I See Circles", 1957 (Box 12, Folder 275)
    - Poems for Carl van Vechten
      - "What" "The Lover" "The Hero's Friend" "Everybody Nobody" "and a Coda 'Pussy willow'", 1957 (Box 12, Folder 276)
    - "Rain", 1957 (Box 12, Folder 277)
    - "Sodom's Rose", n.d.
    - "Song and Ode", 1957
    - "To a Procrastinator", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 278)
    - "To a Whore", n.d.
    - "The Tower", n.d.
    - "Vendra", 1957 (Box 12, Folder 279)
    - "When the yellow lynx", n.d.
  - SHORT STORIES
    - "A Chance to Say No": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 280)
    - "Color of Darkness": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 281)
    - "Daddy Wolf": typescript carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 282-83)
    - "Everything Under the Sun": typescript, carbon (Box 12, Folder 284)
    - "Encore": typescript, corrected, [1957?] (Box 12, Folder 285)
    - "Home by Dark": typescript, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 286)
    - "It's Not Everybody that Can Tell You": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 287)
    - "The Lesson": typescript, corrected, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 288)
    - "Mrs. Benson": typescript, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 289)
    - "Night and Day": typescript, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 290)
    - "O'Reilly Morgan McGowan's Reply to Lady Coyle": typescript, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 291)
    - "Pastor Hill's Sermon on Invincibility": typescripts, corrected, 1957, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 292)
    - "The Pupil": typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 293)
    - "Sermon": typescripts, corrected and photocopy (Box 13, Folder 294-95)
    - "Sonata in 2/": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 296)
    - "Talk About Yesterday": typescript, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 297)
    - "You Reach for Your Wraps": page proof, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 298)
- Other Papers, 1944-72; Series III; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Series III, Other Papers, is housed in Boxes 14-15 and arranged alphabetically by type of material. Works under the heading "Writings of Others" are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Newspaper clippings, 1944-47 (Box 14, Folder 299)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1954-56, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 300)
  - Music by Richard Hundley
    - "Ballad on Queen Anne's Death, 1619", 1964 (Box 14, Folder 300a)
    - "For your Delight", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 300b)
    - "Maiden Snow", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 300c)
    - "Postcard from Spain", 1964 (Box 14, Folder 300)
    - "Softly the Summer", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 300e)
    - "Spring (Shakespeare)", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 300)
    - "Wild Plum", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 300g)
  - Obituaries, 1963, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 301)
  - Printed material, 1954, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 302)
  - Sketches sent to Carl van Vechten
    - "Life in the Empire State": typescript photocopy, 1957-60 (Box 14, Folder 303-09)
    - "Recipes of the Masters, or, the Carlo Magno Cookbook": typescript photocopy, 1957-59, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 310-12)
  - Writings of Others
    - Daiches, David, "A Preface to Malcolm ": typescript, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 313)
    - Fandel, John, "Posies": mimeograph, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 314)
    - G., H. W., "The Cat and the Cur": typescript, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 315)
    - Kolve, Del, "James Purdy: An Assessment" in Time and Tide, 1961 Mar 23 (Box 14, Folder 316)
    - Schott, Webster, "James Purdy: American Dreamer": typescript and printed copy, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 317)
    - Schuyler, George, "The Van Vechten Revolution": offprint, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 318)
    - Seguin, J.A.R., "The Gentlemen's Magazine and the London Bill of Mortality", 1963 Nov 1 (Box 14, Folder 318a)
    - Sitwell, Edith, Taken Care Of: page proofs, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 319)
    - Southern, Terry, The Magic Christian: page proofs, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 320)
- Photographs by Carl van Vechten, n.d.; Series IV; 1.5; (3 boxes)
  Photographs by Carl Van Vechten, Series IV, are arranged alphabetically by subject. Miscellaneous and unidentified photographs are located at the end of the series.
  - Ailey, Alvin, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 321)
  - Allgood, Sara, n.d.
  - Bailey, Pearl, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 322)
  - Bankhead, Tallulah, n.d.
  - Banks, Danny, n.d.
  - Banks, Dick, n.d.
  - Buechner, Frederick, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 323)
  - Burt-Mangeld, Adolfo, n.d.
  - Carroll, Diahann, n.d.
  - Carter, Jack, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 324)
  - Chookasian, Lili, n.d.
  - Claire, Ina, n.d.
  - Colum, Padraic, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 325)
  - Cooper, Gladys, n.d.
  - Cross, James A. (and Wyckoff, William)
  - Daniels, Jimmie, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 326)
  - Davis, Jimmie, n.d.
  - Davis, Ossie, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 327)
  - Dobbs, Mattwilda, n.d.
  - Fatone, Charles, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 328)
  - Faulkner, Trader, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 329)
  - Faulkner, William, n.d.
  - Fitzgerald, Ella, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 330)
  - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, n.d.
  - Franklin, Sidney, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 331)
  - Gibson, Althea, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 332)
  - Gielgud, John, n.d.
  - Gish, Lillian, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 333)
  - Graham, Martha, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 334)
  - Grausman, Philip, n.d.
  - Greenwood, Marianne, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 335)
  - Gross, Chaim, n.d.
  - Hersey, John, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 336)
  - Holiday, Billie, n.d.
  - Hurst, Fannie, n.d.
  - Isherwood, Christopher, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 337)
  - Jones, Earle, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 338)
  - Jones, James Earl, n.d.
  - Jones, Le Roi, n.d.
  - Julian, Doris (Box 16, Folder 339)
  - Kaloah, n.d.
  - Kemp, Tom, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 340)
  - King, Alexander
  - Laing, Hugh, n.d.
  - Lee, Canada, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 341)
  - Leona (?), n.d.
  - McCleary, Stinnette, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 342)
  - Merrick, Alan, n.d.
  - Miles, Lizzie, n.d.
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 343)
  - Miller, Henry, n.d.
  - Moncion, Francisco, n.d.
  - Mostel, Zero, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 344-46)
  - Noble, Sissle, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 347)
  - Olaf, Pierre, n.d.
  - Ortega, Domingo, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 348)
  - Pesenyi, Peter, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 349)
  - Peterson, Louis, n.d.
  - Reiner, Luise, n.d.
  - Rey, Georges, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 350)
  - Robeson, Paul, n.d.
  - Robinson, Bill, n.d.
  - Rodgers, Guy, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 351)
  - Rodriguez, Percy, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 352)
  - Romero, Cesar, n.d.
  - Rorem, Ned, n.d.
  - Sands, Diana (Box 17, Folder 353)
  - Savage, Archie, n.d.
  - Schuyler, George, n.d.
  - Schuyler, Philippa Duke, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 354)
  - Scoll, Harold, n.d.
  - Scott, Zachary, n.d.
  - Sessell, Charles, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 355)
  - Short, Bobby, n.d.
  - Singer, Israel Joshua, n.d.
  - Skipper, William, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 356)
  - Slaff, Bertram, n.d.
  - Smith, Bessie, n.d.
  - Solov, Zachary, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 357)
  - Steegman, Philip, n.d.
  - Stephens, Jack, n.d.
  - Stern, G. B., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 358)
  - Stewart, James, n.d.
  - Stokes, Al, n.d.
  - Sullivan, Maxine, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 359)
  - Tamayo, Rufino, n.d.
  - Taylor, Paul, n.d.
  - Thayer, Al, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 360)
  - Thompson, Claude, n.d.
  - Thomson, Virgil, n.d.
  - Tunney, Gene, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 361)
  - Tynes, Margaret, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 362)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, n.d.
  - Verdy, Violette, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 363)
  - Verrett-Carter, Shirley, n.d.
  - Vidal, Gore, n.d.
  - Vidor, Florence, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 364)
  - Wagner, Bruce, n.d.
  - Wallace, Babe, n.d.
  - Walpole, Hugh, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 365)
  - Warfield, William, n.d.
  - Washington, Fredi, n.d.
  - Waters, Ethel, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 366-67)
  - Webster, Beveridge, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 368)
  - Welch, Elisabeth, n.d.
  - Wescott, Glenway, n.d.
  - White, Carl Darrow, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 369)
  - White, Jane, n.d.
  - White, Josh, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 370)
  - White, Walter, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 371)
  - Wood, Peggy, n.d.
  - Wycka, Ronald, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 372)
  - Yalmon, Junc, n.d.
  - Yow, A. J., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 373)
  - Zimbalist, Efram, n.d.
  - Zorn, Eugene, n.d.
  - Zorn, Robert, n.d.
  - Drawings by James Purdy, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 374)
  - Paintings by Banks, Richard, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 375)
  - New York, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 376)
  - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 377-90)
- Oversize
  Oversize material has been placed here in series order.
  - "The Running Sun: for Soprano and Piano." Music by Robert Helps, text by James Purdy. Autographed score, 1972 Aug (Box 19, Folder 391)
  - 15 illustrations by Eugene Olson, 1961, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 392-406)
  - Illustrations by Ross Roseton, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 407)